<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Digital Business Archives - Tiffin Consulting</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/digital-business/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/digital-business/</link>
	<description>digital business transformation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:47:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/cropped-tiffin-icon-1-150x150.png</url>
	<title>Digital Business Archives - Tiffin Consulting</title>
	<link>/category/digital-business/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>What makes up a DXP</title>
		<link>/what-makes-up-a-dxp/</link>
					<comments>/what-makes-up-a-dxp/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aurovrata V.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Digital Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DXP]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=592</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Following on from the post on the introduction to a DXP platform, this is a post which is part of a series on DXP platforms. Components of a DXP platform The 2022 Gartner report on DXP platforms lists the following components as making up a DXP platform, A Content management tool Ability to organise and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/what-makes-up-a-dxp/">What makes up a DXP</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Following on from the post on the <a href="/an-introduction-to-digital-experience-platforms/">introduction to a DXP platform</a>, this is a post which is part of a series on DXP platforms.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Components of a DXP platform</h2>



<p>The 2022 Gartner report on DXP platforms lists the following components as making up a DXP platform,</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">A Content management tool</h3>



<p>Ability to organise and classify content using taxonomies, meta-fields, through an administrative interface such as the WordPress dashboard tool.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Manage account services </h3>



<p>Ability to create user accounts, track their content, and assign roles with access capabilities constraining what they can see and do on the administrative interface.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Personalisation and context awareness</h3>



<p>Ability to track user behaviour and content preference to provide dynamic content tailored to that user.&nbsp; This requires a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Customer_data_platform">Customer Data Platform</a> to track user data on the site and integrate with the page content in real-time to display relevant content.&nbsp; Context awareness is the ability to display content based on the context of the page and 1st and 2nd party data available about the visitor.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Analytics and optimisation.</h3>



<p>Tools that enable website visitor data and behaviour to be analysed and transformed into information that can be used to further optimise the content, navigation, conversion goals and performance of the website.  Google Analytics is an example of an analytical tool but it lacks the ability to interact with it though an API and retrieve the salient information that results from that analysis.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Customer journey mapping</h3>



<p>Customers might interact with a service on a website, app, chatbot, social platform, customer portal, in-store kiosk, digital stadium billboard, and wearable all in the same day. They’ll want each of those experiences to reflect any interactions they’ve had with the service at any given moment and across any device.&nbsp; This interaction could take place across multiple services/websites that belong to the same entity/group.&nbsp; A DXP needs to be able to follow and map this journey seamlessly.  The DXP platform may use the Customer Data Manager or make use of a Customer Relation Management  service to achieve this.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Customer data management</h3>



<p>A customer’s data will require management and access by employees and may be updated offline too from email/phone interactions with an helpline for example.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Presentation, delivery and orchestration</h3>



<p>The ability to for front-end templating in order to present a cohesive picture across a variety of devices, pulling and combining content from various sources.&nbsp; The presentation is the ability to present a cohesive look and feel to the user across a variety of devices.&nbsp; This variety of devices,&nbsp; which represents the delivery</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Search, navigation and insight</h3>



<p>Ability for all business stakeholders (front-end users/customers, as well as business employees) to search for relevant data, navigate to pages (front-end and backend) in timely and intuitive ways, and presenting data to gain clear insights</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Collaboration and knowledge sharing</h3>



<p>Ability for collaborative content creation, editing, process flows and administration of the digital eco-system in order to ensure timely information flow to stakeholders.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Artificial intelligence</h3>



<p>Machine learning based AI is used primarily for analysing customer data and fine-tuning personalisation engines.&nbsp; <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_Web">Semantic</a> content in order to ease ML content consumption.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Cloud capabilities</h3>



<p>Distributed hosting and content networks as well as cloud-based services</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Architecture and platform design</h3>



<p>Ability to integrate and scale with multiple databases/servers/services in order to mitigate downtime, enhance security, and maintain service performance.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Integration, interoperability and extensibility</h3>



<p>Ability to integrate with various services for the different functionality, such as a CDP or a DAM, while remaining service-agnostic in order to ease transition/evolutions to different platforms.&nbsp; Ability to further extend functionality with plugins and custom development.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Multi-experience support</h3>



<p>Ability to deliver a digital experience across multiple devices in different context.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Security and access control </h3>



<p>Ability to provide secure and controlled access to content to a variety of users, from anonymous visitors, customers, business employees with varying access needs, content creators, editors,&nbsp; and administrators.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A deep dive into the world of DXP platforms</h2>



<p>In the following posts on this series, I will review the existing DXP platform providers, as well as review a DXP solution conceived for the hospitality industry, looking at how DXP platforms can revolutionise the digital experience of hotel guests.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/what-makes-up-a-dxp/">What makes up a DXP</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/what-makes-up-a-dxp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>An introduction to Digital eXperience Platforms</title>
		<link>/an-introduction-to-digital-experience-platforms/</link>
					<comments>/an-introduction-to-digital-experience-platforms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aurovrata V.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Digital Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DXP]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=586</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a series of articles on DXP platforms, and how they are in essence a digital transformation for businesses online. What is a DXP platform? A Digital eXperience Platofrm is the next evolution of websites and web-based applications such as mobile apps and more generally the Internet of Things (IoT). Gartner, the leading technology [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/an-introduction-to-digital-experience-platforms/">An introduction to Digital eXperience Platforms</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This is a series of articles on DXP platforms, and how they are in essence a digital transformation for businesses online.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is a DXP platform?</h2>



<p>A Digital eXperience Platofrm is the next evolution of websites and web-based applications  such as mobile apps  and more generally the Internet of Things (IoT).</p>



<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gartner">Gartner</a>, the leading technology research and consulting firm, has been tracking the evolution of online technologies for businesses and maintain a yearly  <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magic_Quadrant">Magic Quadrant</a>  report that maps the evolving trend in DXP solutions.  Gartner describes a DXP platform as:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>A set of <strong>integrated</strong> technologies to enable the <strong>composition</strong>, <strong>management</strong>, <strong>delivery</strong> and <strong>optimization of contextualized</strong> digital experiences across <strong>multi-experience customer journeys</strong>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>That&#8217;s quite a mouth full, so what is this all about?</p>



<p>Hare are the salient keywords to understand:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>integrated technologies</strong> &#8211; decoupled web services that interact using APIs, exchanging and processing data into a coherent whole. </li>



<li><strong>composition</strong> of experiences &#8211; in addition to web-pages, composition can also include digital media, and these can be tailored for various target audiences.</li>



<li><strong>management</strong> of experiences &#8211; along with web-pages, the ability to manage a plethora of digital assets including media using taxonomies.  This is also the ability to manage the life cycle of this content from ideation, to composition, to review and editing, and publication. This is done in a coherent and collaborative process involving multiple stakeholders from ideation to publication.</li>



<li><strong>delivery</strong> of experiences &#8211; the digital content can be consumed across a variety of devices, including IoT (Internet of Things) connected objects.  In addition, a single end-user of this content interacting with the platform across multiple devices and locations is ensured a seamless and continuous experience.</li>



<li><strong>optimization of contextualized</strong> experiences &#8211; this is ensuring that the digital content consumed by a user is optimized (personalised) for that user based on data available for that user.  This can include their access location, devices and possible other personal data shared by the user previously.</li>



<li><strong>multi-experience customer journeys</strong> &#8211; each user can have multiple digital experiences depending on their previous journeys on the platform as well as other contextualized data points.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Word-of-mouth transformation</h2>



<p>The DXP Gartner report further notes,</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>This digital transformation is best served by customer-obsessed strategies which recognise the new business <em>age of the&nbsp; customer</em> where customers look for seamless digital experience across multiple platforms and will not hesitate to discard a brand over another if unsatisfied with the overall experience, the product or service being only a part of that experience.&nbsp; This transformation values inbound (word-of-mouth, referrals, reviews) marketing over outbound marketing.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In other words, users will automatically promote your product/service if they are satisfied with the digital experience your platform provides.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Optimising and Personalising Content</h2>



<p>Optimising content and personalising to the audience is a key component of a DXP platform, and there are various strategies to achieve it.</p>



<p>Media optimisation becomes important when users access content across different devices.  How many times have you accessed a web page whose images were simply too large or their cropped version irrelevant as the cropped part of the image no longer focuses on the object.  This is especially true with cheap e-commerce sites that have been designed for a desktop experience, but are simply unusable on a mobile screen.  </p>



<p>DXP platforms increasingly rely on AI image recognition to suggest the optimal image cropping for various devices.  These services can even dynamically crop a video frame by frame to ensure the object of attention stays in-frame on a portrait mobile screen rendition, and ensuring an optimal experience for all users.</p>



<p>Personalisation is more tricky to achieve, as any given web-page cannot be dynamically personalised for every single users as this would create tremendous loads on a server.  The majority of web pages are cached in order to speed up their delivery.  Similarly a <em>personalised</em> web page con only realistically have a handful of versions which can cater to user segments.  Here is an article I wrote which goes into more details on the strategies used for <a href="/mitigating-performance-impact-from-personalisation/">optimising performance on page variants</a>.  </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">So what makes up a DXP platform?</h2>



<p>In the next post in this series, I explore <a href="/what-makes-up-a-dxp/">what components actually make up a DXP platform</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/an-introduction-to-digital-experience-platforms/">An introduction to Digital eXperience Platforms</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/an-introduction-to-digital-experience-platforms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Content Creation Tools For Lead Generation Business.</title>
		<link>/content-creation-tools-for-lead-generation-business/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aurovrata V.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 03:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Digital Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lead generation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=414</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A brief review of some available tools for collaborative content creation and management.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/content-creation-tools-for-lead-generation-business/">Content Creation Tools For Lead Generation Business.</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Alone we can do so little, together we can do so much!</p>
<cite><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Helen_Keller">Helen Keller</a></cite></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-group has-border-color has-base-background-color has-background has-global-padding is-content-justification-center is-layout-constrained wp-container-core-group-is-layout-2 wp-block-group-is-layout-constrained" style="border-color:#3c4142;border-width:1px;border-radius:5px;margin-top:var(--wp--preset--spacing--20);margin-bottom:0;padding-top:var(--wp--preset--spacing--10);padding-right:var(--wp--preset--spacing--10);padding-bottom:var(--wp--preset--spacing--10);padding-left:var(--wp--preset--spacing--10)">
<div class="wp-block-group alignwide is-layout-flow wp-block-group-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-left"><em><em>This is a post in a </em><a href="/tag/lead-generation/"><em>series of posts</em></a><em> that explore digital technologies that can be leveraged to amplify a business website&#8217;s capacity to generate leads.  This series builds up the rationale for a business website to undergo its digital transformation in order to provide a user experience more conducive to generate a lead.</em></em></p>
</div>
</div>



<p>Content Management (CMS) platforms such as WordPress have evolved to allow marketing teams to collaborate efficiently with their content writers, media designers and business data analysts, ensuring each team can contribute their expertise in a concerted effort.  The WordPress ecosystem is today the leading CMS platform because it has allowed widely different companies to design and publish their content as per their business specificities. At the core, WordPress content creation has been streamlined to give you access to a single content editor dashboard integrated with a variety of services to allow you to focus on the creation of your message, combining text and media in a well-organised process.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Gutenberg Block Editor</h2>



<p>For example, the creation of a landing page for your online campaign can leverage the Gutenberg block editor, which allows you to compose a page made of a grid of block content.  Each block can be a variety of content running from simple text to headings, images, button, or various other content listings from your own website.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Conditional Block Content</h3>



<p>In addition, each block’s content can be personalised, and although there is a multitude of plugins in the WordPress ecosystem that offers various functionality and out-of-the-box integration with related services, such as <a href="https://logichop.com/get-started/">LogicHop</a> with lead-generating business sites as it is particularly well-suited to personalising content along with out-of-the-box lead scoring functionality.  In addition it has been designed to be easily extensible for custom data integration.  For more suitable conditional content plugins, see this <a href="https://rtcamp.com/blog/personalizing-pages-on-wordpress/" data-type="link" data-id="https://rtcamp.com/blog/personalizing-pages-on-wordpress/">review</a>  by rtCamp WordPress agency.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Digital Asset Management</h2>



<p>Digital media content is an important part of content creation and as such its organisation is important in the context of creating structured content.  A Digital Asset Manager (DAM) is a tool that allows your creative team to organise media content along the same structure as your pages and articles.  This allows your page creators to easily find media that is related to the topic at hand.  DAMs vary in their functionality, from integrating with existing design tools to tracking and analysing media content usage such as <a href="https://www.aprimo.com/">Aprimo</a>, a <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/aprimo-named-a-leader-in-dam-for-customer-experience-by-independent-research-firm-301483832.html">leader</a> in this segment.  However, there are multiple plugins that can fulfil initial requirements for media content management such the simple but excellent <a href="https://wordpress.org/plugins/media-library-assistant/">Media Library Assistant</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Collaborative Content Creation</h2>



<p>Finally, it is important for content creation teams to effectively collaborate on, especially on a landing page where content writers, creative media teams, and marketing conditions need to be orchestrated in order to fulfil a cohesive business communication strategy.  Collaborative editing is complex, and although the Gutenberg editor is yet to offer such functionality (the editor currently locks a page when being edited by a user), there are existing solutions that allow for sequential collaboration on a page.  <a href="https://www.multicollab.com/">Multicolab</a> is a plugin that enables collaborative content creation by enabling annotative functionality within the WordPress dashboard, allowing authors to add comments to specific posts and pages in the editor and tasked to specific users who in turn can resolve them to mark progress.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/content-creation-tools-for-lead-generation-business/">Content Creation Tools For Lead Generation Business.</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Personalising Visitors Journeys On Your Website.</title>
		<link>/personalising-visitors-journeys-on-your-website/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aurovrata V.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 03:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Digital Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lead generation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=403</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to enable dynamic  page content that adapts to your returning users.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/personalising-visitors-journeys-on-your-website/">Personalising Visitors Journeys On Your Website.</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>[&#8230;] you go into a bar and sit down, and the bartender puts a whiskey in front of you without having to ask what you want.</p>
<cite><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeff_Bezos">Jeff Bezos</a>, Amazon.com CEO</cite></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-group has-border-color has-base-background-color has-background has-global-padding is-content-justification-center is-layout-constrained wp-container-core-group-is-layout-4 wp-block-group-is-layout-constrained" style="border-color:#3c4142;border-width:1px;border-radius:5px;margin-top:var(--wp--preset--spacing--20);margin-bottom:0;padding-top:var(--wp--preset--spacing--10);padding-right:var(--wp--preset--spacing--10);padding-bottom:var(--wp--preset--spacing--10);padding-left:var(--wp--preset--spacing--10)">
<div class="wp-block-group alignwide is-layout-flow wp-block-group-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-left"><em><em>This is a post in a </em><a href="/tag/lead-generation/"><em>series of posts</em></a><em> that explore digital technologies that can be leveraged to amplify a business website&#8217;s capacity to generate leads.  This series builds up the rationale for a business website to undergo its digital transformation in order to provide a user experience more conducive to generate a lead.</em>y.</em></p>
</div>
</div>



<p>A business website can be digitally transformed to provide a unique experience for each visitor, not only for each visit, but also for visits by the same user under different circumstances.&nbsp; To achieve this level of personalisation it is crucial to collect a lot of data about users.&nbsp; It does not need to be data that can personally identify the user.&nbsp; A lot can be achieved with robust anonymous data that can reveal trends in behaviour and preferences that correlate directly with your target audience.&nbsp; Robust quality data is only available through robust data collection pipelines that are transparent to your business and not dependent on data aggregators.</p>



<p>Data from online tracking is categorised according to the data collecting party: 1st party data is collected by your own server and its connected services, it is a consequence of the users direct interaction with your online business or other customer touchpoints; 2nd party data is collected by your partner services, it is their 1st party data that you have agreed to share; 3rd party data is collected by data aggregators that collect datasets across a much wider audience, one which your users are only a subset, revealing broader trends which may be less relevant.&nbsp; There is an additional <a href="https://www.forrester.com/blogs/straight-from-the-source-collecting-zero-party-data-from-customers/">zero-party dataset</a>, made of information that is generated by and belongs to the user, and is willingly shared to identify with your brand.</p>



<p>For a long time, many businesses have relied on 3rd party data to market their services and products to their target audience through the use of 3rd party cookies.&nbsp; However, with the <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/danielnewman/2021/12/08/the-move-away-from-third-party-data-is-imminent-are-you-ready/?sh=615304c82093">phasing out</a> of these cookies under increasing privacy concerns and user data-sharing fatigue, it is becoming increasingly important for businesses to <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/marketing/insights/articles/marketers-are-under-a-digital-ad-siege-and-must-now-convince-customers-to-share-data">collect and manage their own data</a> each time a user visits and interacts with their website.&nbsp; Much of this data remains anonymous, but if it is systematically collected and organised such as in a Customer Data Platform (CDP) and analysed using smart algorithms, which increasingly makes use of Machine Learning Artificial Intelligence (AI), fine-grained segmentation of users can be leveraged to personalise the content a user sees on your website.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition, if your business site identifies customers and collects additional data in a Customer Relation Manager (CRM), returning customers (if they sign in or have accepted a tracking cookie), can have their digital experience enhanced by leveraging their historical interaction with your business.&nbsp; Although this applies more often to online retail businesses, it can also apply to lead-generating websites that may have several brands or services for customers to discover and experience.&nbsp; Furthermore, a customer&#8217;s journey recorded in your CDP can link to the CRM and their custom journey represented in your CRM dashboard.&nbsp; This can be extremely powerful if you have multiple touch-points for your customers.&nbsp; For example, a customer help-line, or interactive chat-bot may use this integrated information to seamlessly suggest a continuation of the customer’s journey as they interact with your business ecosystem.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Goals and lead scoring</h2>



<p>Another powerful tool for grading your leads on your website is to define user behaviour goals.&nbsp; These can be as simple as viewing a page, clicking on a Call-To-Action button, registering their email address and so on or possibly based on a 1st party data point such as being referred to your site from an online campaign.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Each goal can be assigned a score such that users accumulated points becomes their lead-score.&nbsp; The lead score can then be updated into your CRM for that user’s profile making it an efficient way to prioritise leads for follow-on actions by your marketing team.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/personalising-visitors-journeys-on-your-website/">Personalising Visitors Journeys On Your Website.</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tracking And Analysing Marketing Campaigns.</title>
		<link>/tracking-and-analysing-marketing-campaigns/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aurovrata V.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 03:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Digital Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lead generation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Tracking your returning users in order to understand what they are seeking from your business website.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/tracking-and-analysing-marketing-campaigns/">Tracking And Analysing Marketing Campaigns.</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>The best marketing strategy: care</p>
<cite><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gary_Vaynerchuk">Gary Vaynerchuk</a>, CEO &amp; Entrepreneur</cite></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-group has-global-padding is-layout-constrained wp-container-core-group-is-layout-5 wp-block-group-is-layout-constrained" style="border-width:1px;border-radius:5px;padding-top:var(--wp--preset--spacing--10);padding-right:var(--wp--preset--spacing--10);padding-bottom:var(--wp--preset--spacing--10);padding-left:var(--wp--preset--spacing--10)">
<p><em>This is a post in a </em><a href="/tag/lead-generation/"><em>series of posts</em></a><em> that explore digital technologies that can be leveraged to amplify a business website capacity to generate leads.&nbsp; This series builds up the rationale for a business website to undergo its digital transformation in order to provide a user experience more conducive to generate a lead.</em></p>
</div>



<p>Have you ever noticed human billboards in high-street shopping areas advertising smaller businesses in side lanes? They are often funny and extremely visible, hard to miss, and they do a great marketing job at getting your attention to a business you would otherwise have never noticed. Online social marketing is akin to human billboards on the high-street, you need to get your business noticed where the crowds hang out. The vast majority of business websites are like these businesses in a slide lane hidden away from the high-street. However, unlike the local high-street, you can advertise your business to all the digital high-streets in the world should you so wish. In reality you want to focus your time and money on those portals where your target client spends their time.</p>



<p>Advertising online with Google or Facebook ads has its merit, there are many more marketing strategies that can lead to better customer experience, which in turn will develop into trust and better engagement. More and more users shy away from online advertising, and 90% of them will research a brand online before making a purchase. Videos are increasingly effective and favoured media for advertising.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Refining Your Marketing Strategy</h2>



<p>A HubSpot <a href="https://www.hubspot.com/state-of-marketing">survey</a> reveals that the use of blogging as a marketing tool increases up to 13x the ROI.&nbsp; It increases the chances of your business being discovered online by users who seek information on this, and therefore are more likely to be converted into a lead.</p>



<p>Given the large number of marketing channels available to a business, how can one go about developing a strategy customised to one’s business?&nbsp; Technology can play a decisive role, allowing marketeers to track and analyse the best performing marketing campaigns.</p>



<p>A marketing content medium can be traced on a given channel by using UTM parameters in the URL of the landing page on the business website.&nbsp; Each campaign will have an associated landing page.&nbsp; Two or more campaigns can link back to the same landing page.&nbsp; Targeted users follow the link to find out more.&nbsp; The URL will include a set of UTM parameters to trace the campaign details such as the source, channel, content, campaign name and even custom keywords.&nbsp; When a user visits the landing page, these UTM parameters can be scanned and stored in a Customer Data Platform to keep a trace of the visit.&nbsp; The UTM values determine the content viewed by the user on the landing page, but more importantly, this accumulated data, from multiple users over multiple campaigns, can be analysed and compared to understand which ones are successful, identify potential trends across time and channels and therefore contribute to the development of a marketing strategy for your business.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Campaign data can be cross-related to data users (see the previous post) to identify the ideal target audience for a given campaign.&nbsp; This systematic and empirical approach to online marketing will ensure a steady and predictable stream of potential leads, both as new and returning customers.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/tracking-and-analysing-marketing-campaigns/">Tracking And Analysing Marketing Campaigns.</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recipe For Optimising A Lead-generating Website.</title>
		<link>/recipe-for-optimising-a-lead-generating-website/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aurovrata V.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 02:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Digital Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lead generation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to tune your business website in order to boost Conversion Rate Optimisation</p>
<p>The post <a href="/recipe-for-optimising-a-lead-generating-website/">Recipe For Optimising A Lead-generating Website.</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Without data you’re just another person with an opinion.</p>
<cite><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/W._Edwards_Deming">Edwards Deming</a></cite></blockquote>



<p><em>This is a post in a <a href="/tag/lead-generation/" data-type="link" data-id="/tag/lead-generation/">series of posts</a> that explore digital technologies that can be leveraged to amplify a business website capacity to generate leads.  This series builds up the rationale for a business website to undergo its digital transformation in order to provide a user experience more conducive to generate a lead.</em></p>



<p>A customer journey on a website starts with a landing page and hopefully ends with a form submission for more information resulting in a lead score.&nbsp; In order to optimise that journey for each visitor we need to measure and analyse the journey in order to better understand it and therefore have the decision-making tools to optimise that path.&nbsp; We cannot assume that one path fits all, as different visitors will be seeking different experiences and information.</p>



<p>The first step is to track our anonymous visitor and store the data.  Where is the visitor coming from on the internet, what is their referral site?  Most of the time these may be a search engine, but maybe they came from a shared social link, or they followed an online campaign. Sometimes, understanding where they are from in the world can play a role in the way they journey/search for information on your website.  What page have they landed on first, which page are they opening next? Are they visiting with a mobile phone, tablet or desktop?  What time of day is it in their locality? Are they bookmarking the page for further reference, or maybe sharing it online?  Have they visited the site before, if so when, what page did they see on that visit?  Have they registered for more information?  Have you stored their details in a Customer Relationship Management (CRM) tool?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">From Website Visitor to Customer: Understanding the Journey</h2>



<p>So many relevant pieces of data that can help to piece together a journey trend with a Customer Data Platform (CDP) analysis tool.&nbsp; Such a tool provides data analysis reports to understand your visitors and to segment them into similar groups in order to predict what a visitor will likely do.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, visitors who are coming to the website in their evening local time may be more inclined to spend time reading various pages on the site, and therefore presenting them with additional recommended pages related to the current landing page may be a better strategy to convince them to sign up for more information.&nbsp; On the other hand, someone visiting on a mobile phone during lunch hour may more likely be wanting to sign up for a demo or an offer on the first page they visit.</p>



<p>To test these different scenarios, a website can have multiple landing pages, or multiple recommended dynamic content on a given page, and the best content/page determined with A/B testing procedures, the result of which are stored in the CDP for analysis. &nbsp; A recent <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/personalized-calls-to-action-convert-better-data">survey by HubSpot</a>, a leading CRM service provider, shows up to 200% increase in lead generation when using dynamic content personalised to the visitor’s current interest.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thus, a business website can be optimised for lead generation for a specific set of target visitors by collecting data and analysing the behaviour of these visitors in order to empirically determine the best design and content that will maximise lead conversions.</p>



<p>As the famous statistician Edward Deming once said, “Without data you’re just another person with an opinion”, measuring and understanding how visitors interact with your site is the objective key to unlocking its potential as a business tool.</p>



<p>Once you have a lead recorded in your CRM, your website can still play a leading role in converting that lead into a sale with intelligent automated marketing tools.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/recipe-for-optimising-a-lead-generating-website/">Recipe For Optimising A Lead-generating Website.</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to generate leads on your business website.</title>
		<link>/how-to-generate-leads-on-your-business-website/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aurovrata V.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 02:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Digital Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lead generation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=378</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Getting your website to work for your business bottom line by fine-tuning it for lead-generation.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/how-to-generate-leads-on-your-business-website/">How to generate leads on your business website.</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>You never get a second chance to make a first impression.</p>
<cite><a href="https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Will_Rogers">Will Rogers</a></cite></blockquote>



<p><em>This is a post in a <a href="/tag/lead-generation/">series of posts</a> that explore digital technologies that can be leveraged to amplify a business website capacity to generate leads.  This series builds up the rationale for a business website to undergo its digital transformation in order to provide a user experience more conducive to generate a lead.</em></p>



<p>Lead generation on a website is as much about reputation and branding as first impressions.&nbsp; A business with a poorly designed website will still get enquiry leads if they have a solid reputation for quality service/product.&nbsp; Similarly, a startup with a well-designed website or mobile app have better chances of scoring leads.</p>



<p>However, even the best designs will fail to attract interest if the business reputation is damaged.&nbsp; A lead today may be a customer tomorrow and therefore a relationship needs to be established from the start and nurtured to build trust, therefore the first impressions matter and chances are new leads will encounter your website first.&nbsp; As <a href="https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Will_Rogers">Will Rogers</a> once famously said, “You never get a second chance to make a first impression!”.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Seek to Improve Your Website</h2>



<p>So what does it take to make a good impression on your business website?&nbsp; This is not an easy riddle to solve, and depends very much on the kind of business you’re in.&nbsp; Some services or products that require a lot of investment (capital and/or time) will require careful and considerable research from the customer before confirming their decision.&nbsp; In such cases, showing a mastery of your craft and being able to communicate the essence of your expertise in a succinct manner, case-studies in hand,&nbsp; will go a long way to establish a good impression.</p>



<p>On the other hand, a business that trades in services/products that have a lot of competition and are fast evolving, needs to distinguish itself from the crowd, and as such be creative in its marketing and design to shine on the first impression, and yet without being intrusive and pushy.</p>



<p>First impressions are not about fancy bells and whistles, and more about functionality and purpose.&nbsp; Do you have the right content, is it relevant to the landing page your visitor found?&nbsp; Does your site load fast as no one likes to wait for pages to load?&nbsp; Is your site navigation intuitive, is it easy for visitors to find the information they need?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Either way, a visitor will eventually need to register for more information and submit their contact information to convert as a lead. However, there is no magic recipe to ensure your website design and content will resonate with your visitors and generate leads, but it is possible to optimise your site through analysis and testing.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/how-to-generate-leads-on-your-business-website/">How to generate leads on your business website.</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rationale for investing in a business website</title>
		<link>/rationale-for-investing-in-a-business-website/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aurovrata V.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 02:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Digital Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lead generation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=374</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Businesses often see a website as a cost rather than an investment, this needs to change to leverage its full potential.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/rationale-for-investing-in-a-business-website/">Rationale for investing in a business website</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“What helps people, helps business.”</p>
<cite><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leo_Burnett">Leo Burnett</a></cite></blockquote>



<p>A website can be much more than a digital window-front for your business.&nbsp; This series of articles explores the rationales for investing into the transformation of a website into a potent business tool.</p>



<p>There are different rationales for business to have a website, and although <a href="https://w3techs.com/technologies/overview/content_management">a 3rd of the Internet</a> , for all practical purposes, is still made up of sites with static content, there has been <a href="https://w3techs.com/technologies/history_overview/content_management/all/y">steady progress</a> towards website platforms with content management systems (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_management_system">CMS</a>), enabling easier content creation and updates as web standards evolved. &nbsp; Whereas static HTML pages needed coding skills to create and maintain pages, the rise of CMS platforms enabled businesses to create and update their website content with little to no coding skills required.&nbsp; On the other hand, this has led to a steady increase in the price of maintaining a website, requiring regular updates, functional customisation as when business demand it.&nbsp; More and more businesses understand that their website is no longer a necessary cost, but rather an investment into their growth.<br>For many traditional brick and mortar retail businesses, CMS platforms have enabled them to transition to online retailing with ecommerce websites, where <a href="https://www.digitalcommerce360.com/article/e-commerce-sales-retail-sales-ten-year-review/">more and more customers</a> prefer the comfort of their home to place their orders online and get their goods delivered, a strong rationale for any retail business to ensure they have a presence online maintained up to date with their latest products and offers.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A business site is a gateway to meet new customers.</h2>



<p>However, even businesses in other industries, may it be service or manufacturing, have an ever-growing rationale to invest into their online presence, as this <a href="https://www.smartinsights.com/content-management/content-marketing-strategy/three-reasons-you-need-to-use-blogging-for-lead-generation/">report</a> points out, business leads increase when a site is updated with regular blogging content.&nbsp; An estimated <a href="https://saleslion.io/ecommerce-statistics/81-of-shoppers-research-their-product-online-before-purchasing/">81% of consumers</a> will research a product or service online before deciding to make a purchase, it is an opportunity for businesses to get leads and build a relationship.&nbsp; As marketing genius, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leo_Burnett">Leo Burnett</a> discovered: “What helps people, helps business”.&nbsp; The more useful the information available to visitors, the more likely they are to sign up for more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Businesses, regardless of their industry, have a strong rationale to leverage their website’s lead-generating potential by investing into the digital transformation opportunities presented by the evolution of technology.&nbsp; So what does it take for a website to become a well tuned lead-generation machine?</p>
<p>The post <a href="/rationale-for-investing-in-a-business-website/">Rationale for investing in a business website</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Tiffin Consulting</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
